# **BRADFORD JOHNSON - DATA ANALYST**

Greenville, SC | 864-905-8853 | BradfordLJohnson@outlook.com | Linkedin | GitHub | Portfolio Site

## **SUMMARY**

Data analyst and recent graduate of the Thinkful Data Analytics program. Proficiency with dashboarding, performance tracking, Pandas, Excel, SQL, Tableau, and Python to transform data into meaningful and easily understood visualizations and presentations. Experience in sociology provides an advantage to understanding problems and analyzing data.

### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

Software: R, Excel, Python, Tableau, SQL, PostgreSQL, PowerPoint

Tools: GitHub, RStudio, Quarto, Anaconda, pgAdmin4

Data Methods: Statistical analysis, data visualization, data cleaning, data exploration, data modeling, A/B testing

Additional Skills: Project management, business strategy, business intelligence, report generation

### **EXPERIENCE**

Thinkful Remote

#### **Data Analytics Program**

06/2022 - 12/2022

- Produced and presented professional projects and presentations focused on business forecasting, price modeling, and statistical analysis.
- Developed skill sets in data analytics systems including Pandas, Excel, PostgreSQL, Tableau and Python, and methodologies including dashboarding, performance tracking, data wrangling, cleaning, and analysis.
- Produced professional projects from concept to completion including:
  Business Analysis Revenue Growth Models Lariat Rent-A-Car | Link
  - Examined and cleaned historical sales data using Excel (VLOOKUP, pivot tables and t-tests).
  - Facilitated exploratory data analysis and assessed by KPI performance.
  - Developed and presented models that showcased a 40% increase in profits.

Statistical Significance - Fuel Economy - EPA Vehicle Data | Link

- Developed a model to assist shareholders in determining factors that drive fuel economy.
- Supported data through t-tests run on fuel price factors showing statistical significance.

Inventory Analysis - Sales Trends - Vending Machines | Link

- Facilitated t-tests to determine the statistical significance between price, type and location of products.
- Developed visualizations in Python and presented data in PowerPoint to highlight inventory strategy to increase revenue.

TopGolf Greenville, SC IT Team Lead 10/2022 – Present

- Repair zones and target infrastructure improving game health for guests by 20%.
- Developed a process to increase confidence in RFID tag error identification by 60%.
- Conduct ad hoc analysis of game KPIs to identify issues and trends.

**Maintenance Technician I** 

03/2022 - 09/2022

### **EDUCATION**

Thinkful Certificate, Data Analytics

Remote 06/2022-12/2022

Winthrop University

Rockhill, SC

**B.A. Sociology** 

08/2017-12/2021